Heather Cooper

HBCooper4@gmail.com / 850.294.2856 / Atlanta, GA

SUMMARY

Resourceful and self-motivated pharmacist with extensive experience in clinical data analysis, evaluation of medical research and literature to prepare reports and presentations. Comfortable in high-volume settings, flexible and able to adapt to retail, office, clinical or field hospital environments.

SKILLS

- Data mining
- Cold chain inventory management
- Clinical medical record and literature review
- Pharmacy, medical and billing claims data analysis
- Proficient in Excel, Word, Power Point
 - Exceptional written and oral communication skills

EXPERIENCE

Pharmacist Site Leader - Emory Health Care COVID-19 Vaccination Clinic AMN-Med Travelers - Atlanta, GA

June 2021 to Present

 Train and supervise pharmacists, pharmacy technicians and nursing staff in proper vaccine dilution and dose preparation. Maintain cold chain inventory management of COVID-19 vaccine products.
 Communicate with administration team to minimize potential wasted doses.

Staff Pharmacist - Mercedes Benz Stadium Community Vaccination Center Jackson Pharmacy Professionals - Atlanta, GA

March 2021 to June 2021

Administered approximately 250,000 doses of Pfizer COVID-19 vaccines during a 10-week period.
Responsible for vaccine inventory and cold chain management in support of the Department of
Defense pharmacy and medical teams, Fulton County Board of Health, Georgia Department of
Public Health, Federal Emergency Management Administration and Georgia Emergency
Management Administration.

Pharmacist - COVID-19 Vaccine Support CVS Pharmacy - Lilburn, GA

December 2020 to March 2021

 Worked as a member of a team of pharmacists and pharmacy technicians to set up vaccine clinics in 25 skilled nursing facilities and assisted living facilities, to provide COVID-19 vaccines to several hundred residents and staff.

Staff Pharmacist

Florida A&M University Pharmacy - Tallahassee, FL

September 2014 to December 2014

 Prepared, verified, and dispensed prescription orders; supervised technician in a community pharmacy within a Florida Department of Health clinic specializing in HIV and sexually transmitted diseases.

Clinical Intelligence Pharmacist Magellan Medicaid Administration - Tallahassee, FL

June 2012 to April 2014

- Monitored prescribing and distribution trends of Florida Medicaid providers using the Medicaid Management Information System (MMIS) through retrospective drug utilization review (RetroDUR) data analysis, to monitor compliance and identify the need for cost-effective clinical system edits.
- Created ad hoc data analysis queries and reports utilizing Business Objects and internal analytic applications to monitor fee-for-service and encounter utilization trends and provided clinical solutions for Florida Medicaid plan administration and Medicaid Program Integrity referrals to promote patient safety, decrease program cost and improve quality of care.
- Analyzed and prepared cost comparisons for new drug therapies; reviewed Pharmacy and Therapeutics (P&T) Committee cost sheets to recommend potential drug criteria, step therapy, and other clinical system edits to ensure patient safety and cost-effectiveness.
- Created drug information documentation, including therapeutic class reviews, quarterly retrospective drug utilization review reports, provider alerts, clinical criteria and clinical system edit recommendations.
- Performed drug utilization analyses, monitored drug pipeline, market events and safety announcements, reviewed literature and evidence-based treatment guidelines to identify therapeutic interventions for RetroDUR activities.
- Prepared and presented the Florida Medicaid RetroDUR Quarterly Report to the Florida Drug Utilization Review Board and Prescribing Pattern Review Panel.

Senior Pharmacist, Medicaid Program Integrity Agency for Health Care Administration - Tallahassee, FL

March 2010 to June 2012

- Prepared and conducted random and focused audits and investigations of pharmacy and durable medical equipment providers, to monitor compliance with the Florida Medicaid Program.
- Performed MMIS claims data analysis for prescription medications, medical equipment, diagnostic and procedure codes to identify fraudulent and abusive behaviors and trends.
- Recovered approximately \$1,500,000 overpayments for the Florida Medicaid Program.

Staff Pharmacist

CVS Pharmacy - Tallahassee, FL

June 2006 to March 2010

 Provided relief coverage in an 18-store district as a floater pharmacist. Responsible for preparation, compounding, verification and dispensing prescription medications and supervised pharmacy staff and interns in the pharmacy department.

Sr. Medical Investigator, Medicaid Fraud Control Unit Office of the Attorney General - Tallahassee, FL

August 2005 to June 2006

 Participated in site visits and inspections of skilled nursing facilities and assisted living facilities to conduct routine reviews or investigations; coordinated with other state agencies and local authorities.

- Advised attorneys and law enforcement investigators in all aspects of case development and data analysis, in reference to prescribing practices, prescription dispensing and compounding, drug information, drug diversion, misuse and abuse trends, to identify and investigate Medicaid fraud and abuse.
- Provided consultation as a subject-matter expert to U.S. State Attorneys, Drug Enforcement
 Administration (DEA) agents, and Florida Department of Law Enforcement (FDLE) investigators, for
 case development and monitoring.

Education

B.S. Pharmacy, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA

Licenses

Registered Pharmacist

- Georgia, RPH019160
- Florida, PS35956
- Pennsylvania, RP44750